<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nonsense on blog // ~ben</title>
    <link>./tags/nonsense.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in nonsense on blog // ~ben</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 16:55:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="./tags/nonsense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonsense</title>
      <link>./nonsense.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 16:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./nonsense.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hole-hardedly agree, but allow me to play doubles advocate here for a
moment. For all intensive purposes I think you are wrong. In an age
where false morals are a diamond dozen, true virtues are a blessing in
the skies. We often put our false morality on a petal stool like a bunch
of pre-Madonnas, but you all seem to be taking something very valuable
for granite. So I ask of you to mustard up all the strength you can
because it is a doggy dog world out there. Although there is some merit
to what you are saying it seems like you have a huge ship on your
shoulder. In your argument you seem to throw everything in but the kids
Nsync, and even though you are having a feel day with this I am here to
bring you back into reality. I have a sick sense when it comes to these
types of things. It is almost spooky, because I cannot turn a blonde eye
to these glaring flaws in your rhetoric. I have zero taller ants when it
comes to people spouting out hate in the name of moral righteousness.
You just need to remember what comes around is all around, and when
supply and command fails you will be the first to go. Make my words,
when you get down to brass stacks it doesn’t take rocket appliances to
get two birds stoned at once. It’s clear who makes the pants in this
relationship, and sometimes you just have to swallow your prize and
accept the facts. You might have to come to this conclusion through
denial and error but I swear on my mother’s mating name that when you
put the petal to the medal you will pass with flying carpets like it’s a
peach of cake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thought of the Day</title>
      <link>./thought-of-the-day22873.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 16:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./thought-of-the-day22873.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Arguing with religious people – It’s like playing chess with a pigeon;
no matter how good I am at chess, the pigeon is just going to knock over
the pieces, crap on the board and strut around victorious” – Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christian Morgenstern – “verkehrte Welt”</title>
      <link>./christian-morgenstern-verkehrte-welt.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 16:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./christian-morgenstern-verkehrte-welt.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dunkel war’s der Mond schien helle, Schnee bedeckt die grüne Flur als
ein Auto blitzeschnelle, langsam um die Ecke fuhr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drinnen saßen stehend Leute, schweigend ins Gespräch vertieft, als ein
totgeschossner Hase, auf der Sandbank Schlittschuh lief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Und der Wagen fuhr im Trabe, rückwärts einen Berg hinauf. Droben zog ein
alter Rabe grade eine Turmuhr auf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ringsumher herrscht tiefes schweigen und mit fürchterlichem Krach,
spielen in des Grases Zweigen zwei Kamele lautlos Schach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Und auf einer roten Parkbank, die blau angestrichen war, saß ein
blondgelockter Jüngling mit kohlrabenschwarzem Haar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neben ihm ne alte Schrulle, zählte kaum erst 16 Jahr, In der Hand ne’
Butterstulle, die mit Schmalz bestrichen war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Droben auf dem Apfelbaume, der sehr süße Birnen trug, hing des Frühlings
letzte Pflaume und an Nüssen noch genug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Von der regennassen Straße wirbelte der Staub empor und der Junge bei
der Hitze mächtig an den Ohren fror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beide Hände in den Taschen hielt er sich die Augen zu. Denn er konnte
nicht ertragen, wie nach Veilchen roch die Kuh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holder Engel, süßer Bengel, furchtbar liebes Trampeltier. Du hast Augen
wie Sardellen, alle Ochsen gleichen Dir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Und zwei Fische liefen munter, durch das Blaue Kornfeld hin. Endlich
ging die Sonne unter und der graue Tag erschien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Und das alles dichtet Goethe Als er in der Morgenröte Liegend auf dem
Nachttopf saß Und dabei die Zeitung las.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
