<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conventions on blog // ~ben</title>
    <link>./tags/conventions.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in conventions on blog // ~ben</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="./tags/conventions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Republican National Convention in Cleveland - Day Four</title>
      <link>./rnc-day-four.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./rnc-day-four.html</guid>
      <description>UPDATE looks like an article of convention notes by two of our reporters ran in the Mining Journal!
Trump is officially the Republican nominee for President of the United States of America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Party of Lincoln</title>
      <link>./the-party-of-lincoln.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./the-party-of-lincoln.html</guid>
      <description>Something that struck me as absolutely outrageous (more than other things that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this week) was the connection of the roots of the Republican party to the modern Republican party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Republican National Convention in Cleveland - Day Three</title>
      <link>./rnc-day-three.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./rnc-day-three.html</guid>
      <description>Something that has been on my mind all week is the utter lack of minority representation at the convention. Inside the security perimeter, most black people that you see are working here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Republican National Convention in Cleveland - Day Two</title>
      <link>./rnc-day-two.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./rnc-day-two.html</guid>
      <description>Our second day at the RNC began once again at the Michigan Delegation Breakfast Session.
Michigan Speaker of the House Kevin Cotter addressed the delegation with a report on the state of the state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Lives Matter? I thought All lives matter</title>
      <link>./blue-lives-matter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./blue-lives-matter.html</guid>
      <description>#BlueLivesMatter completely misses the point. And it makes #AllLivesMatter hypocritical.
This cartoon says it all.
The same people that pioneered the #AllLivesMatter movement are now claiming that #BlueLivesMatter. Do they not understand the irony of this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Republican National Convention in Cleveland - Day One</title>
      <link>./rnc-day-one.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./rnc-day-one.html</guid>
      <description>Michigan delegates to the Republican National Convention got fired up for New Jersey Governor Chris Christie as he addressed them this morning at their first breakfast meeting. Christie stressed the importance of party unity behind the presumptive nominee, Donald Trump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Republican National Convention</title>
      <link>./republican-national-convention.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./republican-national-convention.html</guid>
      <description>I was asked to chaperone a group of youth journalists with 8-18 Media (a youth journalism program in Marquette that I was once a part of)
Disclaimer: these blog posts represent my opinion!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
